Guide to the Institute on the Arts and Civic Dialogue Archive MSS.127
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series 3: 2000, 58177
  - Subseries 3.7: Artist Applications--Rejected and Tentative Rejections, 58210
    - Patricca, Nick, undated; 58289 (Box 12, Folder 1090)
    - Perez, Rudy, undated; 58288 (Box 12, Folder 1091)
    - Perry, Janice, undated; 58287 (Box 12, Folder 1092)
    - Piazza, Michael, undated; 58286 (Box 12, Folder 1093)
    - Pleasant, David, undated; 58285 (Box 12, Folder 1094)
    - Pointek, Gregory, 2000; 58284 (Box 12, Folder 1095)
    - Pope, William L., 2000; 58283 (Box 12, Folder 1096)
    - Quinlan, 2000; 58282 (Box 12, Folder 1097)
    - Rainey, Bhab, 2000; 58281 (Box 12, Folder 1098)
    - Raymond, Monica, 2000; 58280 (Box 12, Folder 1099)
    - Reese, Charles, 2000; 58279 (Box 12, Folder 1100)
    - Reese, Bob, 2000; 58278 (Box 12, Folder 1101)
    - Reese, Venus O., 2000; 58277 (Box 12, Folder 1102)
    - Rho, Sung, 2000; 58276 (Box 12, Folder 1103)
    - Robinson, Walter, 2000; 58275 (Box 12, Folder 1104)
    - Rodriquez, Arthur, 2000; 58274 (Box 12, Folder 1105)
    - Roetter, Joyce, 2000; 58273 (Box 12, Folder 1106)
    - Rohret, Bernice, 2000; 58272 (Box 12, Folder 1107)
    - Rolnick, Neil, 2000; 58271 (Box 12, Folder 1108)
    - Rosen, Craig, 2000; 58270 (Box 12, Folder 1109)
    - Ross, Kwame, 2000; 58269 (Box 12, Folder 1110)
      Contains one VHS video cassette:, 1995.
    - 127.0038, 1996; 58268 (Box 12, Folder 1110a)
      Video recording, VHS, 3M T-20. Stages of Truth (Edited highlights from the feature performance) by the Sands of Time Dance Company; "Promo '95/Version II Final Cut", RT: 16:08, 7/23/96. Submitted as part of the application of Kwame Ross.
    - Rowland, Steve, 2000; 58267 (Box 12, Folder 1111)
    - Ruiz, Roberta, 2000; 58266 (Box 12, Folder 1112)
    - Sahl, Michael, 2000; 58265 (Box 12, Folder 1113)
    - Saint Croix, Judith, 2000; 58264 (Box 12, Folder 1114)
    - Sanders, Edward, 2000; 58263 (Box 12, Folder 1115)
    - Schaeffer, Karin, 2000; 58262 (Box 12, Folder 1116)
    - Schildhaner, Cynthia, 2000; 58261 (Box 12, Folder 1117)
    - Schoenfeld, Howard, 2000; 58260 (Box 12, Folder 1118)
    - Searles, Heather, 2000; 58259 (Box 12, Folder 1119)
    - Shen, Janis, 2000; 58258 (Box 12, Folder 1120)
    - Sherman, Pamela, 2000; 58257 (Box 12, Folder 1121)
    - Shields, Alice, 2000; 58256 (Box 12, Folder 1122)
    - Simon, John, undated; 58255 (Box 12, Folder 1123)
    - Simon, Ken, undated; 58254 (Box 12, Folder 1124)
    - Simon, Patricia, undated; 58253 (Box 12, Folder 1125)
    - Simpson, David, 2000; 58252 (Box 12, Folder 1126)
    - Singer, Beverly, 2000; 58251 (Box 12, Folder 1127)
    - Smith, Andrea, 2000; 58250 (Box 12, Folder 1128)
    - Smith, Trudii, 2000; 58249 (Box 12, Folder 1129)
    - Sogel, Daniel, 2000; 58248 (Box 12, Folder 1130)
    - Solomon, Jeffrey, 2000; 58247 (Box 12, Folder 1131)
    - Soreff, Sasha, 2000; 58246 (Box 12, Folder 1132)
    - Spence, Pamela, 2000; 58245 (Box 12, Folder 1133)
    - Spieler, Sandra, 2000; 58244 (Box 12, Folder 1134)
    - Stahler, Wesley, 2000; 58243 (Box 12, Folder 1135)
    - Snider, David, 2000; 58242 (Box 12, Folder 1136)
    - Sternberg, Wendy, 2000; 58241 (Box 12, Folder 1137)
    - Sullivan, John, 2000; 58240 (Box 13, Folder 1138)
    - Tanjuaquio, Paz, 2000; 58239 (Box 13, Folder 1139)
    - Perrin, Carol, 2000; 58238 (Box 13, Folder 1140)
    - Thorne, David, 2000; 58237 (Box 13, Folder 1141)
    - Tomlin, Liz, 2000; 58236 (Box 13, Folder 1142)
    - Trachtenberg, Barbara, 2000; 58235 (Box 13, Folder 1143)
    - Turner, Jill, 2000; 58234 (Box 13, Folder 1144)
    - Ukeles, Merle, 2000; 58233 (Box 13, Folder 1145)
    - Uzuri, Imani, 2000; 58232 (Box 13, Folder 1146)
    - Vallon, Jean, 2000; 58231 (Box 13, Folder 1147)
    - Van Kuren, Ann, 2000; 58230 (Box 13, Folder 1148)
    - Vega, Carmen, 2000; 58229 (Box 13, Folder 1149)
    - Vitale, Julius, 2000; 58228 (Box 13, Folder 1150)
    - Walot, Francoise, 2000; 58227 (Box 13, Folder 1151)
    - Ward, Melody, 2000; 58226 (Box 13, Folder 1152)
    - Ware, Kendra, 2000; 58225 (Box 13, Folder 1153)
    - Webster, Carol, 2000; 58224 (Box 13, Folder 1154)
    - Weinstein, Larry, 2000; 58223 (Box 13, Folder 1155)
    - West, Liz, 2000; 58222 (Box 13, Folder 1156)
    - Whittlesey, Lorraine, 2000; 58221 (Box 13, Folder 1157)
    - Williams, Liza, 2000; 58220 (Box 13, Folder 1158)
    - Wilson, Pamela, 2000; 58219 (Box 13, Folder 1159)
    - Wise, Nina, 2000; 58218 (Box 13, Folder 1160)
    - Wolf, Marc, 2000; 58217 (Box 13, Folder 1161)
    - Wolper, Andrea, 2000; 58216 (Box 13, Folder 1162)
    - Woods, Allie, 2000; 58215 (Box 13, Folder 1163)
    - Wyrrick, Sharon, 2000; 58214 (Box 13, Folder 1164)
    - Yathin, Nejla, 2000; 58213 (Box 13, Folder 1165)
    - Yves, Mustard, 2000; 58212 (Box 13, Folder 1166)
    - Zhao, Suikang, 2000; 58211 (Box 13, Folder 1167)
  - Subseries 3.8: Artist Applications--Unknown Status, 58178
    This body of applications was preserved as a separate set of files within the IACD records. The series contains a large number of applications from artists involved with the Institute in previous years as well as others. Files are arranged alphabetically by last name.
    - Call to Artists, 2000; 58209 (Box 13, Folder 1168)
    - Akalaitis, Joanne, 2000; 58208 (Box 13, Folder 1169)
    - Arce, Elia, 2000; 58207 (Box 13, Folder 1170)
    - Breuer, Lee, 2000; 58206 (Box 13, Folder 1171)
    - Chong, Ping, 2000; 58205 (Box 13, Folder 1172)
    - Conway, Merry; Pratt, Noni, 2000; 58204 (Box 13, Folder 1173)
    - Cortez-Woolery, Reginald, 2000; 58203 (Box 13, Folder 1174)
    - Diamond, Liz; Picoult, Darcy, 2000; 58202 (Box 13, Folder 1175)
    - Gonzalez, Anita, 2000; 58201 (Box 13, Folder 1176)
    - Goode, Joe, 2000; 58200 (Box 13, Folder 1177)
    - Hoffbauer, Patricia; Sanchez, George Emilio, 2000; 58199 (Box 13, Folder 1178)
    - Jackson, Homer, 2000; 58198 (Box 13, Folder 1179)
    - Katz, Joel, 2000; 58197 (Box 13, Folder 1180)
    - Kim-Trang, Tran, 2000; 58196 (Box 13, Folder 1181)
    - Lanzillotto, Annie, 2000; 58195 (Box 13, Folder 1182)
    - Mason, Keith Antar, 2000; 58194 (Box 13, Folder 1183)
    - McCallum, Bradley, 2000; 58193 (Box 13, Folder 1184)
    - Miller, Tim, 2000; 58192 (Box 13, Folder 1185)
    - Mogul, Susan, 2000; 58191 (Box 13, Folder 1186)
    - Negron-Muntaner, Frances, 2000; 58190 (Box 13, Folder 1187)
    - Perkins, Merle, 2000; 58189 (Box 13, Folder 1188)
    - Portillo, Lourdes, 2000; 58188 (Box 13, Folder 1189)
    - Rhine, Dont, 2000; 58187 (Box 13, Folder 1190)
    - Royals, Demetria; Gonzales, Anita; McCauley, Robbie, 2000; 58186 (Box 13, Folder 1191)
    - Spiegelman, Art; Parks, Van Dyke, 2000; 58185 (Box 13, Folder 1192)
    - Spotted Eagle, Chris, 2000; 58184 (Box 13, Folder 1193)
    - Strom, Mary-Ellen, 2000; 58183 (Box 13, Folder 1194)
    - Swados, Elizabeth, 2000; 58182 (Box 13, Folder 1195)
    - Wright, Jules, 2000; 58181 (Box 13, Folder 1196)
    - Wyrrick, Sharon, 2000; 58180 (Box 13, Folder 1197)
    - Yearby, Marlies, 2000; 58179 (Box 13, Folder 1198)
- Series 4: Video Recordings, 58142
  The majority of these recordings are of performances of works from the IACD. However one recording is of the production of Anna Deavere Smith's House Arrest at the Papp Theater in 2000. Another recording, from the Massachusetts Foundation for the Humanities, bears an uncertain relation to the IACD.
  - Institute on the Arts and Civic Dialogue, 1999; 127.0007; 58159 (Box 14, Cassette 127.0006, 127.0007, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss127_0007)
    Video recording, VHS, Maxell T-15 std, SP, RT: 11:00
  - Institute on the Arts and Civic Dialogue, Off-Line Edit, 1999; 127.0009; 58158 (Box 14, Cassette 127.0008, 127.0009, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss127_0009)
  - Anna Deavere Smith With Bill Barbeaux, Summer 1999, 127.0011; 58157 (Box 14, Cassette 127.0010, 127.0011, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss127_0011)
    Video recording, VHS, Maxell T-30 std, SP, RT: 28:00; summer, 1999.
  - Musical Prayers, Summer 2000, Tape 1, 127.0013; 58156 (Box 14, Cassette 127.0012, 127.0013, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss127_0013)
    Video recording, VHS, Maxell T-60 std, SP, RT: 41:00
  - Musical Prayers, Summer 2000, Tape 2, 127.0015; 58155 (Box 14, Cassette 127.0014, 127.0015, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss127_0015)
    Video recording, VHS, Maxell T-60 std, SP, RT: 44:00
  - Public Art, Public Land by Judy Baca, Tapes #1-3, undated; 127.0017; 58154 (Box 14, Cassette 127.0016, 127.0017, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss127_0017)
    Video recording, VHS, Maxell T-90 std, SP, RT: 1:21:00, undated
  - High Noon, Tapes #1, 3, 5, 7, 9, undated; 127.0019; 58153 (Box 14, Cassette 127.0018, 127.0019, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss127_0019)
    Video recording, VHS, Maxell T-160 std, SP, RT: 2:13:00
  - Brandon, Tapes #1, 3, 5, 7, 9, undated; 127.0021; 58152 (Box 14, Cassette 127.0020, 127.0021, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss127_0021)
    Video recording, VHS, Maxell T-180 std, SP, RT: 2:33:00
  - Brandon, Tapes #A1-A5, undated; 127.0023; 58151 (Box 14, Cassette 127.0022, 127.0023, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss127_0023)
    Video recording, VHS, Maxell T-160 std, SP, RT: 2:29:00
  - House Arrest, Tapes #1A-5A, IACD workshop production, undated; 127.0025; 58150 (Box 14, Cassette 127.0024, 127.0025, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss127_0025)
    Video recording, VHS, Maxell T-160 Pro, SP, RT: 2:37:00
  - Anna Deavere Smith, House Arrest, Act I. New York Production, 2000; 127.0027; 58149 (Box 14, Cassette 127.0026, 127.0027, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss127_0027)
    Video recording, VHS, Maxell T-90 std, SP, RT: 1:14:00, Recorded 4/13/2000
  - Anna Deavere Smith, House Arrest, Act II. New York Production, 2000; 127.0029; 58148 (Box 14, Cassette 127.0028, 127.0029, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss127_0029)
    Video recording, VHS, Maxell T-90 std, SP, RT: 1:00:00, Recorded 4/13/2000
  - Common Infractions: Gross Injustices, Tape #1B, undated; 127.0031; 58147 (Box 14, Cassette 127.0030, 127.0031, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss127_0031)
    Video recording, VHS, Maxell T-30 std, SP, RT: 23:00
  - The Minstrel Show, Tapes #1,2, undated; 127.0033; 58146 (Box 14, Cassette 127.0032, 127.0033, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss127_0033)
    Video recording, VHS, Maxell T-60 std, SP, RT: 59:00
  - The Minstrel Show, Tapes #3,4, undated; 127.0035; 58145 (Box 14, Cassette 127.0034, 127.0035, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss127_0035)
    Video recording, VHS, Maxell T-90 std, SP, RT: 1:02:00
  - Massachusetts Foundation for the Humanities, Stories to Be Told; The Unfound Door; Chautauqua Institution, undated; 127.0037; 58144 (Box 14, Cassette 127.0036, 127.0037, Box Digitized Access Files, File mss127_0037)
    Video recording, VHS, Maxell T-60 std, SP, RTs: 10:40, 7:50, 21:10 (TRT: 41:00)